Bhagyashree Hemant Parkar Frontend Developer

parkarbhagyashreehs@gmail.com | +1 (347) 506-4475 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Prolific, task-driven **Frontend Developer** with 4 years of experience developing client-focused ADA-compliant websites and web projects in a fast paced environment using HTML, CSS, PHP, Angular, React, Python, TypeScript and JavaScript across diverse industries. Proficient in developing databases, creating user interfaces, writing and testing codes, debugging, and implementing new advanced functionalities based on client feedback. Strong interpersonal and communication skills, with a track record of building and maintaining positive relationships with clients, and team members

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages : C/C++, C#, Python, Java

Databases : MySQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, PostgreSQL

Web Technologies : ReactJS, Redux, JSON, Angular, NET, ASP, WebPack, Babel, Rest APIs, NPM,

Node.js, Vue.js, Express.js, Web3, Bootstrap, Next.js, Responsive design,

JQuery, Sass, Test-driven Development, Version Control, Saas

Development Platforms : WordPress, Salesforce, Drupal, Hubspot, Woocommerce, AEM, JIRA, Asana

Basecamp, Bitbucket, Git, Grunt, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Analytics, Azure,

Visual Studio, Docker, AWS, SendGrid, Atlassian, BrowserStack, Papyrus

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Dream Chase Technology, LLC

Feb 2024 – present | Brooklyn NY, USA

- Directed daily operations by managing workflow while evaluating client project requirements to ascertain feasibility and devised strategic steps to accomplish objectives effectively according to industry trends
- Demonstrated ability to translate business requirements into solutions on Amazon Web Services (AWS) that
 align with business goals, along with mentoring junior developers and administrators, providing training on best
 practices and advanced AWS features
- Proficient in building web applications and website utilizing WordPress, WP Engine, AEM, Drupal, HubSpot, E-Commerce, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, and PHP, ensuring responsiveness
- Demonstrated advanced proficiency in front-end and back-end development technologies and frameworks, such as React.js, Angular, Vue.js, and Express.js, as well as server-side logic, databases, and APIs using technologies like Node.js, Python, Ruby and PHP
- Optimized the performance of web applications through efficient coding practices, server-side optimizations, and caching strategies

Web Developer | Changing The Present

Feb 2023 - Jan 2024 | Remote, USA

- Developed and managed WordPress from scratch by integrating with front-end user-friendly web functionalities using HTML CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React, and Angular along with other Content Management Systems
- Gained hands-on experience with Salesforce CRM by assisting in the customization and configuration of Sales Cloud and Service Cloud to meet specific business requirements of the organization for selling products
- Supported agile development and deployment of custom Salesforce Lightning Components to enhance user interface, user experience for internal teams as well as web accessibility
- Collaborated in the integration of third-party applications with Salesforce using REST and SOAP APIs, enhancing system capabilities and data consistency across platforms
- Utilized Amazon Web Services (AWS) to deploy and manage applications, leveraging AWS services such as EC2, S3, and RDS for scalable and reliable solutions

Web Developer | Technosoft Engineering Projects Ltd.

Jun 2019 - Jul 2021 | Thane, India

- Achieved 98.56% client satisfaction by developing responsive websites to meet client requirements with a 95% quality check score and 97.85% accuracy in both front-end and back-end, in a B2B or B2C web production
- Led the optimization of the company's website, resulting in a 75.65% increase in website scores compared to the previous best and significantly improving website efficiency, navigation, and overall user experience
- Optimized sites for 96.87% usability, search engine optimization, easy navigation, ADA compliance and accessibility, meeting clients' requirements
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities in identifying and resolving technical issues for seamless website
 functionality along with enhancing page speed up to 92% for Mobile and 99% for desktop view using Google
 Pagespeed Insights and GTMetrix for maintaining best web performance and webflow
- Mastered BI and SEO tools including SEMRush, Ahrefs, Optimizely, Crazy Egg, Conductor, Google Analytics, Google Webmaster tools, Google Tag Manager, and emerging technologies, maintaining security and stability
- Mentored and managed developers for building email templates, landing pages, and websites on Hubspot using Hubl and other tools resulting in an overall production increase of the company by 80% in content management
- Implemented SQL stored procedures to fetch data for SSRS reports, enhancing data retrieval efficiency as well
 as executed daily database updates for multiple websites, managing various features and capabilities
 seamlessly

Web Developer Intern | Othrys Media (OPC) Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2018 - June 2019 | Thane, India

- Designed and developed a well-designed company website from scratch using industry best practices, contributing to creating user-friendly website layouts and interfaces with HTML/CSS, Javascript, and PHP
- Actively participated in maintaining and troubleshooting the website, ensuring optimal functionality across various browsers and devices through comprehensive testing procedures
- Fostered effective collaboration with web designers and team members, translating visual designs into functional web elements and working together to meet client specifications and technical requirements
- Managed content management tasks on WordPress, including updating website content and optimizing SEO practices to enhance content relevance, freshness, and search engine ranking
- Maintained meticulous technical documentation for website maintenance and updates, streamlining the process for team members and clients and ensuring continuity and ease of site management

IT Intern | Western Marine Traders

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 | Mumbai, India

- Assisted in the development of new web pages or features under the guidance of senior developers as well as learned and applied coding standards for HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other relevant technologies
- Updated and managed website content via content management systems (CMS) like WordPress as well as
 ensured all website content was up-to-date, accurate, and aligned with SEO best practices and web services
- Conducted website testing to identify bugs and ensure compatibility across different browsers and devices and assisted in the testing of website performance, including loading times and web responsiveness
- Participated in project meetings and contributed ideas for improving website functionality, design, and user experience while collaborating with cross-functional teams, including design, marketing, and content creation teams, to support web projects

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Rutgers University

Sep 2021 - Dec 2022 | New Jersey, USA

Major: Information Technology and Analytics

GPA: 3.3

CGPA: 7.76

Relevant coursework: Software Development, Data Structures and Algorithms, Business Intelligence

Bachelor of Engineering,

Jul 2015 – Jun 2019 | Mumbai, India

K. J. Somaiya Institute of Engineering and Information Technology

Major: Information Technology